securustech.net 2019-05-04

# Privacy - Securus Technologies

##### PART I: GENERAL PRIVACY POLICY

This privacy policy describes how Securus uses and protects the information we collect about you, our customers and the users of our products and services, including detainees currently incarcerated in a correctional facility. All purchases or users of Securus products and services, as well as visitors to our website, are subject to this privacy policy. Part II of this Privacy Policy sets forth additional policies related to purchases or users of Securus’ Video Visitation services (SVV). Part III of this Privacy Policy has some additional general terms that apply to all users of the Securus website or our products or services. By accessing and using our website, or any of our products or services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

###### A) What information do we collect?

We collect information from you when you open an account or register for online account access. You may be asked, by a live agent, computer, telephone, mobile device or otherwise, to provide your name, date of birth, social security number, e-mail address, mailing address and phone number. You may be asked to provide a credit card number and associated information for certain services. We may also collect other personal information when you purchase or use our products or services, including your location data, voice data, and video data.

We may also collect certain information automatically when you visit our website and interact with it, such as device or computer identifier, MAC address, IP address, location information, and a record of your use and browsing on the website. As described below, we may use cookies or other similar tracking technologies to help use recognize you, provide a personalized experience to you, and understand how you use the website.

Some Internet browsers include the ability to transmit “Do Not Track” signals. Since uniform standards for “Do Not Track” signals have not yet been adopted, we do not process or respond to “Do Not Track” signals.

###### B) What do we use your information for?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  1. To process transactions, manage your account and administer our services and website. We will not sell or give your personal information to any other commercial company without your consent, except as is necessary to provide you with the products or services requested or as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy;
  2. To send you periodic e-mails pertaining to your order, as well as occasional Securus news, updates, and related product or service information;
  3. To personalize your experience and better respond to your individual needs); and
  4. To improve customer service, our website and services and assess our services).

Where permitted by law, we may share your information with our affiliates, service providers, and vendors for the above purposes.

###### C) How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety and security of your personal information when you open an account or otherwise provide, enter, submit, or access your personal information. We offer the use of a secure server. All sensitive/credit information you supply online is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and encrypted into our payment gateway provider’s database. There, it is accessible only by those employees and agents with special access authorization rights who are required to keep the information strictly confidential. Upon completion of a transaction, your private information (e.g., credit cards or debit card number, bank routing or checking account numbers) will not be stored on our servers. While we have implemented reasonable physical and electronic data security measures to protect the security of all personally identifiable data we collect, no Internet or communications system can be guaranteed to be absolutely secure, however. By using our system, you agree that we will not be liable for any interception, misuse, alteration or infiltration of your data as a result of any unauthorized access or data breach incident.

###### D) Do we use cookies?

Yes. Securus uses cookies on our website in two limited contexts, both for the sole purpose of assisting you in the use of your account and our website. Cookies are used when a user enables either of these two features: 1) choosing to view the full site when accessing our website via a mobile device; or 2) choosing to have the website remember your information when logging into our website. The first type of cookie lasts only for the duration of the browsing session; the second type lasts for one year, and can be disabled or enabled as you select. By using our website, you consent to our use of cookies. The “Help” section of most website browsers will provide more information on how to manage cookies, including how to block, delete or receive notification when a cookie is being set on your computer or device. More details regarding cookies in the context of Securus’ video offerings are described below.

###### E) Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer your personally identifiable information to third parties for commercial purposes. We may share your personally identifiable information with third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or providing services to us or to your account, as necessary for the provision of such services. We may also release your information to enforce our website policies, or protect our or others rights, property, or safety, or as required by law in response to subpoenas, warrants or other lawful order. We reserve the right to transfer your personally identifiable information and all other data pertaining to you and your use of our services or products in the event of a transfer, merger, reorganization, acquisition or dissolution of all or part of our business or assets.

###### F) Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may offer third party products or services on our website or include links to third party websites. These third party websites have separate and independent privacy policies. We have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

###### G) Information used in connection with and in support of law enforcement activities

We may share your contact information, account information and history when you open and account, as well as call details, location information and your voice and video records when you use our telephone or video services with law enforcement personnel and/or correctional facilities and certain third parties for use in connection with and in support of law enforcement activities. Any calls or visits using our services may be monitored or recorded for law enforcement purposes, and location, voice, video and other data collected and analyzed for law enforcement purposes.

###### H) Our Additional Privacy Policies with respect to Securus Video Visitation

Our additional Privacy Policies with respect to Securus Video Visitation (SVV) are set forth in more detail below.

###### I) Changes to Your Information and to our Privacy Policy

  1. If your contact or other information changes or is incorrect, please contact us or change it by accessing your Account Profile online.
  2. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and we reserve the right to do so at our discretion. Any changes shall take effect immediately unless otherwise required by law. We will notify you of changes in advance in cases required by law.

###### J) What are your choices for how we use your information to communicate with you?

You can choose how we communicate with you. For example, if at any time you would like to cease receiving emails from us, please follow the opt-out process that is provided near the bottom of any email from Securus. If you receive text message notifications from us, you can unsubscribe from your text notifications at any time by replying STOP to any text message, online with Securus Online by editing your Notification Settings, or over the phone by calling Customer Care 1-800-844-6591.

##### PART II. ADDITIONAL PRIVACY POLICIES IN REGARD TO THE SECURUS VIDEO VISITATION (SVV) PRODUCT

In addition to the terms set forth above, the following shall also apply to purchases or users of SVV: 

###### K) Access by Governmental Authorities

Purchasers and users acknowledge, understand and agree that the SVV session and the data collected in the use of SVV will be accessed, reviewed, analyzed, searched, scrutinized, rendered searchable, compiled, assembled, accumulated, stored, used, licensed, sublicensed, assigned, sold, transferred and distributed by personnel involved in the correctional industry (federal, state, county and local), investigative (public and private), penological or public safety purposes and specifically including the Department of Homeland Security and any other anti-terrorist agency (federal, state and local) (collectively, “law enforcement”).

###### L) No Responsibility

You agree that Securus assumes no responsibility for the activities, omissions or other conduct of any member of any correctional facility or law enforcement. Relative to SVV, Securus acts solely as a portal for the online distribution and publication of electronically distributed information and has no obligation to screen communications or information in advance and is not responsible for screening or monitoring electronic communications sent via SVV service. Securus has no liability or responsibility to users for performance or nonperformance of the SVV service. Securus may take any action with respect to user submitted information that it deems necessary or appropriate, in its sole discretion. 

###### M) General

Securus is committed to providing a means by which detainees currently incarcerated in a correctional facility may establish electronic communication with the user -using SVV. The use of SVV is conducted pursuant to the terms hereof. We want to provide a helpful user experience, but one where all participants understand that the contents of any and all such SVV as well as the information relating to the transfer of money may be accessed, reviewed, analyzed, searched, scrutinized, rendered searchable, compiled, assembled, accumulated, stored, used, licensed, sublicensed, assigned, sold, transferred and distributed by correctional facilities and law enforcement personnel. As such, you should not have any reasonable expectation that your use of SVV service, or the contents of SVV communications are, or will remain private and/or protected by any legal privilege 

###### N) Personal Information About Securus Video Visitation Users

When you sign up to use the SVV service, you must provide Securus with certain personal information such as name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card number, etc. We will use this information primarily in connection with efforts to provide the SVV service. You understand, acknowledge and agree that this information may be shared with law enforcement and that we may use and compile that information as part of our responsibilities to law enforcement. As a result, you understand, acknowledge and agree that you will not have an expectation of privacy concerning the contents of any account information. 

###### O) Information that we automatically receive

In addition to the information you provide to us when you establish your SVV account, Securus receives and stores certain information whenever you participate in SVV. For example, and as noted above, Securus uses cookies. We do this so that we can recognize you when you visit our website. Additionally, we identify the numerical IP address assigned to your computer by your Internet service provider. 

###### P) Use and Disclosure

The personal information collected also allows us to provide users with private and secure areas to prepare a profile for their use of the SVV service. You can correct or update your profile at any time by logging into our website using your username and password in order to implement such corrections or updates. Securus shares information with companies that help us process transactions such as credit card processors. Securus may also disclose information that we in good faith believe is necessary to investigate fraud or illegal activity, or to conduct investigations of violations of our Agreement. Securus will disclose information requested by a regulatory or government authority investigating illegal activities. Similarly, we will disclose your personal information whereby our company or business assets are transferred to a third party or if we are compelled to do so by law. 

###### Q) Visits

These terms apply to all persons who participate in or observe any SVV sessions, as well as to account holders and other users of any Securus product or service. 

###### R) Recording

You agree and understand that SVV sessions may be recorded and monitored without prior notification. Some user types, as defined by the correctional facilities, will not be subject to recording and monitoring. 

##### PART III – Additional General Terms

###### S) Transfer of Data to the United States.

Securus’ website and business are operated in the United States and are intended for users located in the United States. The privacy and data protection laws in the United States differ from those of other countries. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that the information that we collect will be transferred to and processed, stored, and used in the United States, and that by using our site and applications, you consent to such transfers and processing in the United States. 

###### T) Children’s privacy

This website and our products and services are not directed to children. We do not knowingly seek or collect personal information from children under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verified parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you learn that a child’s information has been provided to us, please contact us as soon as possible as provided below. 

###### U) Your California Privacy Rights

This Privacy Policy describes how we may share your information for marketing purposes, as described above. California residents are entitled to request and obtain from us twice per 12-month period information about any of your collected personal information, including the categories of information collected, the categories of sources from which personal information is collected, the business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling any personal information, categories of third parties with whom we share your information, categories of your information sold or disclosed for any business purpose, and the specific pieces of information we have collected about you. We will deliver the required information to a California resident free of charge within 45 days of receiving a verifiable request from the consumer. The time period to provide the required information may be extended once by an additional 45 days when reasonably necessary, provided you are given notice of the extension within the first 45-day period. The disclosure shall cover the 12-month period preceding Securus’s receipt of the verifiable request and shall be made in writing and delivered through your Securus account, if you maintain an account with Securus, or by mail or electronically at your option if you do not maintain an account with Securus, in a readily useable format that allows you to transmit this information from one entity to another entity without hindrance. Securus shall not require you to create an account with Securus in order to make a verifiable request. Pursuant to California law, we will not discriminate against any California resident for exercising the rights provided in this paragraph, including but not limited to denying access to goods or services, charging different prices, or providing a different level or quality of goods and services. To request this information and for any other questions about our privacy practices and compliance with California law, please contact us toll-free at 1-800-844-6591, through our website at https://securustech.net, or at the mailing address provided below.

###### V) General Disclaimer and Release

By using this website and any product or service offered by Securus, you agree that you will not hold Securus, or any of our affiliates or licensees, responsible or liable for any actions, omissions or other conduct of any authorized recipient of any of your personally identifiable or any other information, including but not limited to any correctional or law enforcement personnel. You further hereby release and forever discharge Securus, our affiliates, licensees, correctional and/or law enforcement facilities and personnel from any and all liability, expense, cost or remedy which may arise as a result of your use of our website, products or services, as well as the use of any information or data as described above. Your use of this website and any product or service offered by Securus is at your own risk, and without any representation or warranty. 

###### W) Contact Us

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, practices, or your use of our site or services, please contact us by phone at 972-734-1111 or by mail to the following address:

Securus Technologies, Inc.  
4000 International Parkway  
Carrollton, Texas 75007
